<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FMS Writes</title>
    <description>Short Stories in Science Fiction and General Fiction written by Frank Michael Sanchez
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 16:21:18 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 16:21:18 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Break Up with Splatoon 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Splatoon 2 barely peaked my interest when it was announced for the Switch. I skipped the demo Nintendo released a month before the launch, thinking it wasn’t for me with its kiddie aesthetic. Even though I love shooters like Halo and Doom, Splatoon 2 looked too frantic for me to be able to keep up with from the let’s plays I had seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;Switch with Splatoon Amiibo and Toy&quot; /&gt;(http://localhost:4000/assets/img/posts/DSC_8756.jpg)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When launch day for Splatoon 2 came, I went against my initial judgment and bought the game, based on two reasons. For the first time, I had a small group of friends who were dying to play a multiplayer game together. This helped solve one of my biggest complaints I have with online multiplayer games, playing with random players from the community and not being able to coordinate between everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second was that I was dying for new game experiences on the Switch. Up until Splatoon 2, I had only three games I would play on the Switch; all of which I was already getting worn out playing. I loved my Switch and wanted to play any game I could on it, even if I wasn’t amazed by the trailers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I purchased Splatoon 2 with little to no expectations other than having $60 worth of entertainment out of it. Not only was my hope met, for almost a solid three weeks Splatoon 2 took over my life. Every day I would jump into the lobby, trying to catch a few matches in the morning before I went to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All me and my friends talked about in our group chat was trying to improve our win-loss ratio, or debating which weapon we thought was the best. I checked the Switch app nonstop throughout the day, trying not to miss any of the shirts and hats that were released when I was away from my Switch. When they released a leather jacket, and I missed it, I was agitated for not being on the ball to grab it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game shattered my expectations. The fast paced three-minute matches were a blast. Even the unique clothing and modification system, which I was expecting to hate, was straightforward and fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;Sad Splatoon Player&quot; /&gt;(http://localhost:4000/assets/img/posts/DSC_8763.jpg)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, after three weeks, breaks in my love of Splatoon 2 started to show. Even though I was playing anytime I could during the day, I never matched the amount of skill and hours many of the other players had already devoted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not long after the second week, I was competing with people almost ten levels above me. My win-loss ratio dropped drastically, and every day I struggled to return to my previous ratio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;Lobby with unbalanced players&quot; /&gt;(http://localhost:4000/assets/img/posts/DSC_8758.jpg)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a break for a few days to focus on writing and work. The urge to play eventually came back but was quickly squashed when I signed back on. Other players were leaps and bounds above my level, yet I was still matched against them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I switched to playing support for my team, focusing on painting every inch of the map I could while avoiding the opposing team at all costs. While this was fun for a while, but it never had a significant impact on the match, causing my team to lose consistently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few days of struggling to keep up, I gave up and stopped playing Splatoon 2. I returned to my PS4, with Crash Bandicoot Remastered and Horizon Zero Dawn, leaving my Switch in its dock waiting for a new game to be released to pull me back in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now a month later, the Splatoon 2 icon is still on my Switch home screen. I scroll past it whenever I’m looking for another game to play, hoping to open it one day and relive the initial excitement I had for the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of me is dying to go back to Splatoon 2, with its vibrant colors and slick shooting mechanics. Unfortunately, until matchmaking is balanced I still can’t enjoy the game. I’m hoping if Nintendo wants Splatoon 2 to be their flagship online shooter for the Switch, they need to get at least the basics of matchmaking correct.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 05:50:06 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/10/My-Break-Up-with-Splatoon-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/08/10/My-Break-Up-with-Splatoon-2.html</guid>
        
        <category>post</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Falling in Love With the Star Wars EU</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first teaser for the Force Awakens was a mix of emotions for me. Everything was there from sandy landscapes, Stormtroopers, X-Wings, and even an amazing Millennium Falcon sequence with the Star Wars overture blasting in the background. Even when the second trailer was released, I got a little choked up seeing Han and Chewy back on the Falcon. I was convinced that this movie would bring back the child in me that loved the original series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width:100%;height:0;padding-bottom:45%;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/MERqXOYXX9hzW&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/gifs/millennium-falcon-MERqXOYXX9hzW&quot;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a warm winter day in Florida when all of my close friends and I were standing outside a movie theater waiting. We took turns running to the bar next to the movie theater for bathroom breaks, water, and snacks. I felt that incredible sense of community that everyone who saw the original trilogy talked about back in the 70s. It was an amazing experience I will never forget. I was finally going to have &lt;em&gt;my own&lt;/em&gt; Star Wars trilogy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything unraveled once Kylo Ren spoke his first line of dialogue. He sounded like a poor copy of Darth Vader, thrown into the film for fan service. I pushed aside my criticism, knowing that the original trilogy wasn’t perfect. Unfortunately, the rest of the movie wasn’t spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-stop callbacks, inferior clones of characters from the original trilogy, and the copied conflict that was already copied for Return of the Jedi made this movie fall flat for me. At first, I thought it was me being too critical of a franchise I grew up with; I struggled to watch it in one setting when it released on Blu-ray. After three attempts to watch the film again, I decided the new direction for the series wasn’t for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width:100%;height:0;padding-bottom:42%;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/3oeSAzIlhqTvDGu83m&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/gifs/starwars-movie-star-wars-3oeSAzIlhqTvDGu83m&quot;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I still have hope that the Last Jedi will turn the series around and pull me back in, it isn’t looking very promising. From all of the pre-press information and interviews, this sounds like another carbon copy of the original series. My biggest hope when Disney announced a continuation of the original series was that we would see new characters, conflicts, and settings that were fresh and built off of what was already in the franchise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, since this doesn’t seem to be the strategy for Disney, I decided to turn to a part of the Star Wars franchise I had mostly ignored growing up, the Extended Universe. (When Disney bought Lucasfilm they changed the name of  the Extended Universe to Legends, but I strongly disagree with that decision, so I will still call it the Extended Universe)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-extended-universe&quot;&gt;The Extended Universe&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/posts/DSC_8744.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Picture of EU content&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I distinctly remember seeing the endless shelves of Star Wars books at the public library or Barnes and Noble. Since the original trilogy was enough for me as a kid, I never jumped into that world of Star Wars. Now, with no satisfying Star Wars stories being told on the silver screen, besides Rogue One which wasn’t half bad, I decided to jump into the EU for new stories and characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EU has everything you would ever want from the Star Wars franchise including numerous books, comics, and some rather good video games. Some of the stories in the EU are so well written, Disney is already pulling from them as is the case with the introduction of Grand Admiral Thrawn in Star Wars Rebels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;books&quot;&gt;Books&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/posts/DSC_8743.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Thrawn Series&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most vibrant area of the EU is the countless books published during the past two decades. No matter what aspect of the Star Wars franchise you love, there is a high chance that a book, or series of books, were published by Lucasfilm. Everything from Rogue Squadron, to Boba Fett stories, have been published and builds upon the original trilogy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great jumping on point for the EU is the Thrawn trilogy of novels by Timothy Zahn. These books take place immediately after the events in Return of the Jedi and build off of the ending of the original trilogy. Before the purchase of Lucasfilm by Disney, these three novels were considered the “Authorized continuation of the legendary Star Wars saga.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zahn’s writing captures the excitement and awe of the Star Wars franchise and successfully builds upon its foundation with the introduction of new characters and lore. The biggest additions to the Star Wars franchise in this series is the introduction of the cunning Grand Admiral Thrawn. His advanced military training, coupled with his logic oriented decisions make him one of the greatest adversaries Luke and his friends have ever had to fight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a great list of the top Star Wars books based on reader reviews, the Goodreads community maintains a &lt;a href=&quot;Goodreads link for top Star Wars books&quot;&gt;large ongoing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;comics&quot;&gt;Comics&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/posts/DSC_8746.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Boba Fett Comics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucasfilm has been publishing comics exploring the vast reaches of the Star Wars universe ever since A New Hope. Most of these comics were published by Dark Horse, and are now collected in handy omnibus collections available both physically, and digitally. All of these comic series is packed with new stories and characters that build on the Star Wars franchise we all know and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first comics I remember receiving as a kid was Enemy of the Empire. I only had the final issue of the four part miniseries, but I read that issue cover to cover countless times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Boba Fett never captured my attention in the original trilogy, the story is very well written and includes a glimpse into the life of Boba Fett and Darth Vader before the events of A New Hope. As with most Star Wars comics, the art compliments the fantastic writing and feels like a Star Wars film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story arc builds out the relationship Darth Vader had with Boba Fett before the events of A New Hope and concluded with an incredible battle between the two characters. If you are interested in the life of bounty hunters in the Star Wars universe or are just a fan of Darth Vader and Boba Fett, this is an excellent introduction to the EU comics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;video-games&quot;&gt;Video Games&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/posts/DSC_8741.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Shadows of the Empire Video Game &amp;amp; Toys&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucasfilm over the years had their fair share of hits and misses when it came to Star Wars branded video games. Titles such as Battlefront and Rogue Squadron were great games that saw wild success and still have a devoted following to this day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the best Star Wars EU game is still Shadows of the Empire for the Nintendo 64. While the game mechanics and controls did not age well, the story is amazing. Set between the events of Empire Strikes Back and Return of the Jedi, Shadows of the Empire tells the story of the search for Han Solo after he is frozen in carbonite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the Thrawn trilogy of novels, Shadows of the Empire introduces another fascinating villain, Prince Xizor. His plot to overthrown Darth Vader, and replace him as the Emperor’s right hand, is captivating and unique. Every level of the game takes place in a well-known part of the Star Wars universe, as well as a few new locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Star Wars EU is a vibrant piece of the franchise that builds and improves on the original trilogy. Stories introduce complex and unique villains and characters that are at times, better than the ones explored in the film franchise. Whether you a disappointed with Disney’s new direction, or want new stories to captivate and entertain you, the Star Wars EU is the best place for you to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 05:50:06 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/09/Falling-In-Love-With-the-Star-Wars-EU.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/08/09/Falling-In-Love-With-the-Star-Wars-EU.html</guid>
        
        <category>post</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reviving the Classic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I vividly remember the first time I used a Macintosh. During a trip to Circuit City to purchase my mother’s iPod Mini, there was a display unit of an iMac G4. Initially it wasn’t the Macintosh that grabbed my attention; instead, it was the looping demo of a game called Nanosaur. I loved dinosaurs as a kid, and still do, so the game instantly pulled me in with its dinosaur theme and stunning graphics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/posts/DSC_8708.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iMac G4 running Nanosaur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Still an amazing game after all this time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I played the demo for a while, I finally noticed the Macintosh running the game. I had always thought computers had to be beige or gray metal boxes that were basic. The iMac G4, with its clean white aesthetic and transparent bubble speakers, changed the way I thought about computers forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/posts/DSC_8772.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;First MacBook&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;My very first MacBook, do kinda miss the jet black color&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I purchased my first Macintosh a few years later when my Compaq laptop was dying of old age. It took a bit of convincing of my parents to purchase a Macintosh since all of their past computers were simple PCs. Thanks to the Macintosh’s excellent marketing and wide-range of apps, they eventually agreed, and we picked out a [year] black MacBook. The first day I turned it on was amazing. From its cheerful startup chime to the Welcome Video that played when you first booted into Mac OS X Tiger, it was an amazing first experience with a Macintosh. After learning Mac OS X and the iLife/iWork suite of applications, I started to research the Macintosh’s long history. It didn’t take long before the candy colored G3s, and sunflower G4s became computers I wanted to collect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years after that first Macintosh turned on, I was finally able to purchase my first Classic Macintosh during a family trip to Seattle. Growing up in a small town in Florida meant that there wasn’t a huge demand for technology, especially for Apple products. I knew Seattle should have a large selection of used computers floating around at garage sales and on Craigslist. Almost immediately I found a reasonably priced Power Mac G4, not my first choice for a Classic Macintosh, but I wasn’t trying to be picky back then. A few email exchanges later and we purchased the Macintosh from the seller who had been using it as an audio mixing station for a few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/posts/DSC_8691.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Power Mac G4 Tower&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Still working to this day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Macintosh was in great shape with almost no scratches, and it ran flawlessly. During all of the excitement of finally finding a Classic Macintosh, I had not thought of how I would transport it back to Florida. Shipping was out of the question due to its heavy weight, leaving my only option to be disassembling it and packing all of the parts into our luggage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/posts/DSC_8693.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Power Mac G4 Tower Inside&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Apple used to make it easy to repair or upgrade your computer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the modular design of the Power Mac G4, the disassembly was painless and quick, but what came next wasn’t. I worried the entire trip home, from when the baggage handlers tossed the luggage onto the plane, the five-hour flight, and the hour ride home from the airport. The next morning I woke up early and excited to reassemble the computer, hoping that none of it was damaged during the trip. After I put it all back together,  the moment of truth finally came. I pressed the power button, and it instantly lit up followed by the startup chime, marking the beginning of my Classic Macintosh Collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a recent move from Florida to Las Vegas, I was unpacking my collection and trying to decide what to do with all of the Macintoshes. I unpacked one of the iMac G3s and turned it on. Being one of the most recent Macintoshes I had bought before the move, it still had Mac OS 9 installed and a bunch of old software from the previous owner. I played around with it for a while and was reminded of why I loved collecting these classic computers from long before I was a daily Macintosh user. Since I had moved cross country with all these cumbersome and unwieldy Macintoshes, I figured I should do something productive with all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;Reviving the Classic&quot; alt=&quot;Reviving the Classic&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/logo.png&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/logo-2x.png 2x&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is where Reviving the Classic comes from. The goal with this website is to document the rich history of the Macintosh through detailed software reviews, repair manuals, and most importantly, retrospectives on the Macintosh platform as a whole. I hope to document a piece of Apple’s history that many of today’s iPad, iPhone, and Watch wearing fans of Apple may not be aware of. Hopefully, this site can be a mix of entertainment and history lessons that everyone can enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 05:50:06 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/10/Reviving-the-Classic.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/07/10/Reviving-the-Classic.html</guid>
        
        <category>post</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
